Fly away home.
Lady Bird is a drama, comedy film directed by Greta Gerwig.
Lady Bird McPherson, a strong willed, deeply opinionated,
artistic 17 year old comes of age in Sacramento.
Her relationship with her mother and her upbringing are questioned
and tested as she plans to head off to college.
Lady Bird McPherson, played by Saoirse Ronan.
Marion McPherson, played by Laurie Metcalf.
Larry McPherson, played by Tracy Letts.
Danny O'Neill, played by Lucas Hedges.
Kyle Sheible, played by Timothée Chalamet.
Julie Steffans, played by Beanie Feldstein.
Lady Bird is a 2017 American coming-of-age comedy drama film written and directed by Greta Gerwig in her solo directorial debut, starring Saoirse
Ronan, Laurie Metcalf, Tracy Letts, Lucas Hedges, Timothée Chalamet, Beanie Feldstein, Stephen McKinley Henderson, and Lois Smith.
Set in Sacramento, California during the early 2000s, it focuses on a high
school senior who has a turbulent relationship with her mother.
Filming for Lady Bird took place from August to
October 2016 in California and New York.
It premiered at the 44th Telluride Film Festival on September 1, 2017, and was released theatrically in the United
States on November 3, 2017, by A24, grossing $79 million, becoming their highest-grossing film at the time.
The film received widespread critical acclaim, with high praise drawn to Gerwig's
screenplay and direction, and the performances of Ronan and Metcalf.
It is considered by many critics as one of the best films of 2017 and
one of the best films of the 2010s and the 21st century.
Lady Bird was chosen by the National Board of Review, the American Film
Institute, and Time magazine as one of the top ten films of 2017.
At the 90th Academy Awards, it earned five nominations: Best Picture, Best Actress (for Ronan),
Best Supporting Actress (for Metcalf), Best Original Screenplay, and Best Director.
At the 75th Golden Globe Awards, the film won two awards—Best Motion Picture (Musical or Comedy) and
Best Actress in a Musical or Comedy (for Ronan)—and was nominated for two others.
It was also nominated for three British Academy Film Awards.
The film was released with a soundtrack.
The film explores themes of friendship, loss of virginity,
coming of age, teen angst, high school graduation.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional and thought_provoking.